Ryan Rotman

Georgetown, TX 78626 | Phone: (707) 291-7221 | Email: ryan.rotman@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedin.com/ryanrotman | GitHub: github.com/ryanrotman

Portfolio: <u>ryanrotman.github.io</u>

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with skills and knowledge in problem solving, technical environments, management of staff, and training. Strong interpersonal, organizational, and communication skills will contribute to the success of a team. Earned a Certificate of Completion in Full-Stack Web Development from the University of Texas at Austin Coding Boot Camp. Background in customer service has shown the value and importance of building relationships with those being served and will bring that same heart and passion to any organization and client.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, AJAX, JSON

Applications: Terminal, Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, Node.js, Express,

Handlebars, MySQL, MySQL Workbench, Sequelize, Heroku, MongoDB, Robo 3T, Webpack, React

Models: OOP, TDD, ORM, MVC, CRUD, PWA

PROJECTS

SHAKR APP | https://bit.ly/ShakrAppCode | https://bit.ly/ShakrApp

- SHAKR App! A cocktail generator web-app that uses the Cocktail DB.com and Google Maps API to render cocktail recipes based on user-submitted ingredients on-hand and/or show a map of bars or grocery stores.
- Core Responsibilities: Handling the Bulma CSS Framework and layout of card elements, Google Maps API, Modal layout and application that takes in user input, makes the API call, and renders the new map
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API theCocktailDB & Google Maps, Bulma

It's a Blog's Life | https://bit.ly/BlogsLifeCode | https://bit.ly/BlogsLifeApp

- A full-stack weblog app built on NodeJS using express-sequelize, handlebars, Passport, and ESLint. Share your thoughts, find new friends, and give feedback to others content in the form of comments and likes!
- Core Responsibilities: Front-end design of the site, layout utilizing grid system and mobile responsiveness, styling using Materialize, back-end AJAX POST calls for blogpost likes.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars, Sequelize, Passport, MySQL, Heroku, JawsDB, ESLint

EXPERIENCE

Specialty Coffee Association Coffee and Events Coordinator Santa Ana, CA 2018 - 2019

- Served as Inventory Manager maintaining equipment, new supply procurement, inventory control, and coordinating third party warehouse handling, managing all content and users
- Optimized supply inventory for maximum cost effectiveness to stay within budget restrictions managed 400+ SKUs and restructured to less than 100 by organizing inventory into kits to reduce the number of line items ordered and improve accuracy of items arriving at events
- Directed visits for 4 origin trips to coffee producing countries including itinerary, registration setup, visa applications/letter of invitations from hosts, and pre, during, and post-trip communication with all attendees, staff and hosts

- Collaborated with education department to coordinate instructors and supplies needed to present workshops and classes
- Conducted 2 large-scale and 5 small-scale Barista Guild events oversight of event staff, volunteers, and content, coordination of logistics including event manning, setup and tear down optimization, supplies, as well as shipping and receiving of all association owned and sponsored supplies and equipment

Taylor Maid Organic Coffee (now Taylor Lane Organic Coffee) Lead Barista and Trainer

Sebastopol, CA 2013 - 2018

- Oversaw the day-to-day operation of two coffee bars and 2 to 10 baristas during scheduled shifts
- Organized the thoughtful and effective training for new and seasoned team members as well as over 50 local business partners - focused on technical coffee skills, hospitality and people-connection soft skills, and company values
- Managed and enhanced staff development through staff interviews, hiring, assigning and scheduling trainings, communication with appropriate staff on new hire status growth, and maintaining an ongoing training schedule

Power Industries Santa Rosa, CA IT Technician 2010 - 2013

- Partnered with management in the implementation of new inventory and purchasing software
- Performed required information updates on the system

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

Certificate - Full-Stack Web Development

Cedarville University

Cedarville University

Cedarville, OH

Bachelor of Arts - Music

Austin, TX

Cedarville, OH

Cedarville, OH

2002 - 2007

ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND ACTIVITIES

- Microsoft Office (Outlook, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Office 365, Teams)
- Google Suite
- Slack
- Quick learner and adopter of technology, programs, and software
- Eagle Scout